Jeremy Crichton

♥ Vancouver, BC, Canada

Profile

I'm a software engineer with experience developing fast, scalable cloud applications. I recently built Jade, a framework for deploying JAMstack applications on AWS infrastructure. I'm also a Canadian CPA with extensive experience in corporate finance and was previously Chief Financial Officer of several public companies.

Professional Experience

2020 – present Vancouver, Canada	Co-Creator, Software Engineer jadeframework.dev Co-created an open source framework for deploying JAMstack applications Deployed and configured a flexible AWS infrastructure Built a Node.js app running on EC2 to handle build and deployment Built a Node.js CLI and React / Node.js admin panel for developers Utilized Docker to isolate individual application build environments in EC2 Built Jade project website with Gatsby.js and deployed with Jade on AWS
2018 – 2020 Vancouver, Canada	 Full Stack Web Developer Papersword B2B Marketing Built web applications, custom Wordpress templates and marketing websites for a variety of companies
2009 – 2016 Vancouver, Canada	 Vice President, Corporate Finance Fiore Management & Advisory Corp. Chief Financial Officer of several publicly listed companies responsible for all financial reporting and continuous disclosure requirements Advised on corporate structuring and reporting for initial public offerings, reverse takeovers, and financing transactions
2007 – 2009 Vancouver, Canada	Audit Senior Deloitte & Touche LLP Carried out audits of public and private companies and earned CPA designation

Education

2018 – 2020 Remote	Software Engineering, Web Development Launch School, launchschool.com/employers ☑ A rigorous program building strong fundamentals in software engineering and web development utilizing a mastery-based learning pedagogy.
2008 Canada	Chartered Professional Accountant CA School of Business

2004 **Bachelor of Commerce** Victoria, BC, Canada *University of Victoria*

Skills

Languages & frameworks

Javascript (ES6), Node.js, Express, React, Redux, Ruby,
Rails, Postgresql, MongoDB

Cloud

AWS, Docker